Mss.526.92.G62
American Philosophical Society
Notebook; maps, ca. 1850-1880
Circa 1850-1880
Mss.526.92.G62
American Philosophical Society
1.0 Volume(s) 1 volume, 200 p.
The notebook includes descriptions of land surveys in Wayne County, Pennsylvania, and notes in various hands on early history and settlers there. The maps include boundary descriptions, and there are copies of two deeds.
1 volume, 200 p.
Goodrich, B. G.
Volume 1
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Purchased from Harold Nestler (Auto 1983, #159; $65.00) and accessioned, 1983 (1983 532ms).
Biographical/Historical note
B. G. Goodrich worked as a Pennsylvania surveyor.
Early American History Note
This volume contains a wide range of land surveys in western Pennsylvania, especially Wayne County. There are also pieces on the history of the county and some brief biographical profiles.
Commonplace Book; Land speculation; Maps and Surveys; Maps.; Notebooks; Notebooks.; Real property -- Pennsylvania -- Wayne County.; Surveying and Maps; Wayne County (Pa.) -- History -- 19th century.; Wayne County (Pa.) -- Surveys -- 19th century.
- Survey Maps (Oversize 1)
  - Draft of land sold by Richard Doney to Chauncy Demming, 12 April 1854; 1 survey, 30.5 x 20.1 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Other Finding Aids note
    Realms of Gold, 18 (1).
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Oversized.
  - Lot of lands which Hugh Connor purchased of Abrm Brink, 15 May 1856; 1 map, 21 x 16 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Realms of Gold, 18 (2).
  - McMullen survey for Aldens, July 1857; 1 map, 23 x 20 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Realms of Gold, 18 (3).
  - Draft of Oliver Stevenson's land and mill pond in Mount Pleasant, May 1859; 1 map, 58 x 43 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Realms of Gold, 18 (4).
  - Harvey D. Williams tract. Scott Township, 1 October 1859; 1 map, 31 x 20 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Realms of Gold, 18 (5).
  - Bate Saw Mill, 28 February 1863; 1 map, 31.5 x 20 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Realms of Gold, 18 (6).
  - David C. Boyd road, n.d.; 1 map, 31 x 19.5 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Scope and Contents note
    "Draft of the road described in The Annual Return with courses and distances."
    Realms of Gold, 18 (7).
  - John Mung's land, 1 map, 17 x 13 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Realms of Gold, 18 (8).
  - Joseph Bodie's home farm. Dyberry Township, Wayne County, Pennsylvania, n.d.; 1 map, 27.5 x 22 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Realms of Gold, 18 (9).
  - Land sold by D. W. Manning to Christian Hartung, 1 map, 32 x 20 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Realms of Gold, 18 (10).
  - Patterson Hartshorn land, 1 map, 43 x 35 cm; Goodrich, B. G.
    Realms of Gold, 18 (11).